<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fort Wayne Real Estate Video Blog with David Brough</title>
    <description>Our mission at Anthony REALTORS is to be your best resource for Fort Wayne real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Anthony REALTORS, your professional Fort Wayne Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 11:52:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 11:52:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Most Important Rooms to Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTr5OTAwmIA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home sellers want to know what buyers are most drawn to in a home and, as such, are often curious about &lt;strong&gt;the specific rooms to make a priority when getting their property ready for the market.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two rooms, in particular, that buyers will put a premium on as they look for their new home—the first of which is &lt;strong&gt;the kitchen.&lt;/strong&gt; That may not come as much of a surprise to you, but the kitchen tends to be a center of activity within the home; time with family is spent in this part of the home, and it’s a primary spot for entertaining guests. It makes sense, then, that buyers want the kitchen to be in top condition and move-in ready. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning to sell in a few years or sooner, &lt;strong&gt;concentrate your efforts on replacing the countertops and mismatching appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; Getting a set of matching, mid-grade appliances can go a long way—especially since mismatching appliances tends to not go over well with a lot of buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Getting a set of matching, mid-grade appliances can go a long way.%20http://localhost:4000/2-most-important-rooms-to-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Getting a set of matching, mid-grade appliances can go a long way.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second room that buyers will take a careful look at is &lt;strong&gt;the master bathroom&lt;/strong&gt;, so if yours is looking passé, consider doing some updates. If you’re planning to move soon, upgrading the room in its entirety is probably not a wise investment; &lt;strong&gt;give more attention to replacing items like flooring and countertops and less attention to replacing fixtures.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden tub is one bathing fixture that seems to be on its way out in terms of buyer popularity. As a bonus tip, homeowners who plan on staying long-term and who have one of these tubs could replace it with a tiled walk-in shower and really see that investment pay off when it comes time to sell later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to best improve your home or if you need recommendations for some great contractors to assist you with that, please reach out to us. We’re always here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 13:47:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-most-important-rooms-to-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2-most-important-rooms-to-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How an Offer Letter Helps You Stand Out</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BNsiZs-irv0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we head into the spring selling market, we’re going to see more and more multiple-offer situations occur, so today I’ll share a secret that will help get your offer accepted when competing against more than one buyer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One way to stand out is by sending in a buyer offer letter.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a short, one-page document that appeals to the seller from an emotional standpoint. When they receive multiple offers, all they see is numbers and names. Including this letter allows you to stand out from the pack and make a personal connection with the seller. Your offer will include a story about you, your family, and why you love the house so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I highly encourage you to utilize this strategy.%20http://localhost:4000/how-an-offer-letter-helps-you-stand-out.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I highly encourage you to utilize this strategy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve found great success when producing an offer letter with our buyers’ offers. &lt;strong&gt;I highly encourage you to utilize this strategy if you plan on buying a home in 2019. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what our offer letters look like or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 15:50:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-an-offer-letter-helps-you-stand-out.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-an-offer-letter-helps-you-stand-out.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Renting vs. Owning: Which Is Better?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ClZgO9fXCDo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many long-time renters are now starting to consider whether it’s a good time to take the plunge into homeownership. I recently hosted a Facebook Live session where I discussed this point exactly, and I’m excited to share that full interview with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:47 — Why should Fort Wayne residents consider buying a home over renting one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;04:33 — What are the drawbacks of renting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;05:42 — Are rent-to-own properties worthwhile, and, if so, what kind of people is this option most viable for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;09:26 — How should those looking to buy in the next year get started with their search?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:02 — How can buyers and sellers contact Anthony Realtors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call, send us an email, or visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortwaynehomehub.com/first-time-buyers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.fortwaynehomehub.com/first-time-buyers/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:02:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/renting-vs-owning-which-is-better.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/renting-vs-owning-which-is-better.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons Every Seller Should Consider an Open House</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rPg0HLGKTqg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of misconceptions out there about open houses. Some assume that this popular marketing technique is no longer effective, but this couldn’t be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main reasons why today’s sellers must remain open to the idea of hosting an open house:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Open houses create urgency.&lt;/strong&gt; Sunday tends to be the most popular day of the week for open houses. Not only does hosting this event on the weekends maximize the number of buyers able to attend, but it also creates the opportunity to build excitement in the preceding days. If you list your home on a Tuesday, for example, and advertise that there will be an open house the following Sunday, this gives buyers plenty of time to get excited about your home. Open houses also allow buyers to see exactly how much competition they’re up against. This creates a sense of urgency and incentivizes buyers to put their best foot forward when making an offer. With that said, don’t turn away attractive offers just because you’ve already accepted one. Leave the opportunity for buyers to submit backup offers open, in case your current deal falls through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you know what buyers like, and dislike, about your home, you’ll be much better equipped to present it in a way that fits their expectations.%20http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-every-seller-should-consider-an-open-house.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you know what buyers like, and dislike, about your home, you’ll be much better equipped to present it in a way that fits their expectations.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Open houses are a great way to get feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers are looking for the best possible place to call their next home. Therefore, the majority of those who attend an open house are going to give their honest opinions. Criticism can be hard to receive, but it can also be a very helpful tool. When you know what buyers like, and dislike, about your home, you’ll be much better equipped to present it in a way that fits their expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Open houses are a good marketing tool.&lt;/strong&gt; As I mentioned before, the best time to hold an open house is the first Sunday after it’s been listed. The next best time, though, is around the third or fourth week the home has been on the market. When we host another open house at this point, we are able to leverage this in our marketing to reach new buyers who might have entered into the market. Assuming you’ve made the appropriate adjustments, this can give your listing a renewed level of buyer interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 13:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-every-seller-should-consider-an-open-house.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-every-seller-should-consider-an-open-house.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2019 New Year Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P8mYJu3GoKA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we begin 2019, there’s a lot of news coming out of our Fort Wayne market that I’ll discuss with you today in my latest Facebook Live interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of the full conversation so you can jump ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:20—Are we in a buyer’s or seller’s market? &lt;br /&gt;1:21—What does inventory look like?&lt;br /&gt;2:31—How is inventory affecting home values? &lt;br /&gt;3:30—What do interest rates look like? &lt;br /&gt;4:54—What do all of the numbers mean for buyers and sellers as a whole?&lt;br /&gt;9:29—If you want to sell now, how can you find out your home’s value? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have a great 2019 no matter what your real estate goals are. If you have any questions for me or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-new-year-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-new-year-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get a Better Credit Score With These 2 Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/spzlV-HQqNo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us would love to improve our credit scores, whether you’re already on the brink of hitting 850 (the highest possible score) or you’re struggling to break into the 700s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one in every 200 people maintains an 850 credit score, but if you follow the two credit-boosting tips we’ve got for you today, you could soon count yourself among them. Even just getting to 750, though, will put you in the good graces of most lenders out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Surprisingly enough, having a zero balance is not ideal.%20http://localhost:4000/get-a-better-credit-score-with-these-2-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Surprisingly enough, having a zero balance is not ideal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here are today’s tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Set up automatic payments for all recurring bills.&lt;/strong&gt; According to creditcards.com, about 35% of your credit is based upon your payment history. Having your bills paid automatically out of your account each month will save you a lot of time, help you avoid late fees, and build your credit all at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pay attention to your credit limit.&lt;/strong&gt; Banks don’t look too kindly upon accounts with maxed out lines of credit. It makes you appear less responsible. Instead, experts recommend keeping your credit balance at or below 30%. Surprisingly enough, it’s actually preferable to have between 10% to 20% of your balance remaining, as a zero balance is not ideal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/get-a-better-credit-score-with-these-2-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/get-a-better-credit-score-with-these-2-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Latest Fort Wayne Market Snapshot</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3gRPu7-LraA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;What’s the latest news from our Fort Wayne market? Inventory is shrinking, but home prices remain affordable. Here are a few key statistics comparing our current fall market to what we saw at this time last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;First, there have been 450 fewer new listings that have come on the market compared to this time last year, which is a 4.7% decrease. The number of pending sales also decreased compared to this time last year, to the tune of 1.6%. Year to date, there have been 200 fewer closed sales compared to last year, which is a 3.1% decrease. The average sale price, meanwhile, is up 9.1%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We've been in a seller's market for the past two to three years, so we're probably due for a slight correction.%20http://localhost:4000/your-latest-fort-wayne-market-snapshot.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve been in a seller’s market for the past two to three years, so we’re probably due for a slight correction.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the past two years, home values have appreciated 20%&lt;/strong&gt;, which is pretty significant considering Fort Wayne has traditionally been known as a market with little-to-no appreciation. The most significant statistic of all, though, is 17%—that’s how much inventory dropped this past September compared to September 2017. Since we’re a smaller market, there aren’t a lot of homes to choose from anyway. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall, our market is undergoing a slight shift.&lt;/strong&gt; Interest rates are at a seven-year high, and as prices become less affordable, fewer buyers will want to enter the market. At that point, inventory will increase and balance things out between buyers and sellers, which is a good thing. We’ve been in a seller’s market for the past two to three years, so we’re probably due for a slight correction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any more questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-latest-fort-wayne-market-snapshot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/your-latest-fort-wayne-market-snapshot.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Live Discussion on Multiple-Offer Situations</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iMJ07DMdWlw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take a closer look at how to navigate multiple-offer situations when selling a home, I hosted an in-depth discussion about the best ways to handle the process. In this live-chat, you’ll find the answers to important questions that many sellers have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve placed timestamps for each topic of discussion that we cover. Feel free to navigate to the section(s) you are most interested in viewing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(00:34)—In our current market, are we seeing a lot of multiple-offer situations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(01:01)—From a buyer’s standpoint, is offering the most money the only way to win?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(04:20)—How important is it to be pre-approved when bidding on a home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(05:20)—If you’re expecting multiple offers, what should you do before listing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(06:43)—After receiving some offers, should you decide right away or wait?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(08:07)—Are there ever times you &lt;strong&gt;shouldn’&lt;/strong&gt;t take the highest offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(10:17)—How to reach me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I invite you to contact me if you’re looking to buy or sell, have any questions, or would simply like some information. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-live-discussion-on-multiple-offer-situations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-live-discussion-on-multiple-offer-situations.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Reason to Consider Selling This Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/spzlV-HQqNo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it pays to go against the crowd. While a lot of people think the spring is the best time to put their home on the market, that’s not necessarily true. In Fort Wayne, September and October are great months for real estate and there are three reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. There’s less competition.&lt;/strong&gt; Since a lot of homeowners are waiting for the spring, the fall is a great time for you to get your home on the market and quite possibly be the only one for sale in the neighborhood. Less competition is good for sellers and gives them much more leverage. If a buyer is looking for a home in your area or price range, that puts you in a very strong negotiating position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The fall is a great time to make a move up.%20http://localhost:4000/2-reason-to-consider-selling-this-fall.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The fall is a great time to make a move up.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Buyers are more serious.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of times, these people have more of a timeline and want to get into a house by the holiday season. This means they will be motivated to get a deal done. There will be fewer buyers total, but the ones out there will be much more serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your listing photos will look fantastic.&lt;/strong&gt; While the grass is still green and the leaves are changing colors, getting photos taken for your home’s online listing during this time will be your best pictures. Your first showing is online, so you can make it as great as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or you’re on the fence about selling this fall, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-reason-to-consider-selling-this-fall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2-reason-to-consider-selling-this-fall.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
